Men, are you over 40?
40살이 넘었습니까?
When you wake up in the morning,
do you feel tired and rundown?
아침에 일어날 때
피곤하신가요?
Do you have that listless feeling?
기분이 우울하십니까?
- Jefferies.
- Congratulations, Jeff.
- 제프리입니다
- 축하하네, 제프
- 뭘?
- 깁스를 풀어서
- For what?
- Getting rid of that cast.
Who said I was getting rid of it?
내가 깁스를 풀었다고
누가 그러던가?
This is Wednesday.
오늘이 수요일이니까
Seven weeks from the day
you broke your leg. Yes or no?
다리 부러진 지
7주가 지났잖나, 안 그런가?
Gunnison, how did
you get to be such a big editor
그런 기억력으로
어떻게 편집장까지 올라갔나?
With such a small memory?
Thrift, industry and hard work...
근검과 노력
And catching the publisher
with his secretary.
그리고 사장이 비서와
놀아나는 걸 봤거든
- Did I get the wrong day?
- No.
- 날짜를 잘못 짚었나?
- 아니
No, wrong week.
주일이 틀렸어
Next Wednesday I emerge from this...
Plaster cocoon.
다음 주 수요일에 풀 거야
That's too bad, Jeff.
Well, I guess I can't be lucky every day.
정말 안됐군
사람이 매번 정확할 순 없으니까
전화는 안 한 걸로 해두게
Forget I called.
Yeach, I sure feel
sorry for you, Gunnison.
그래
정말 안됐네, 거니슨
Must be rough on you thinking of me
wearing this cast for another week.
한 주일을 더 기다려야 할 테니
자네가 힘들겠어
That one week is gonna cost
me my best photographer,
난 최고의 사진기자를
And you a big assignment.
자넨 특종을 놓치게 된 거야
Where?
어딘데?
There's no point
in even talking about it.
말해봤자 뭐해
Oh, come on, come on. Where?
말해봐, 어디야?
Kashmir. Got a code tip from
the bureau chief this morning.
케시미르, 아침에 고위층에서
제보가 들어왔어
완전 박살이 날 거라는데
The place is about to go up in smoke.
내가 뭐랬어?
그 곳이 수상하댔지?
What did I tell you? Didn't I tell
you that's the next place to watch?
- 그랬지
- 언제 떠날까, 1시간 후?
- You did.
- When do I leave? Hour?
- With that cast on? You don't.
- Stop sounding stuffy.
- 깁스를 두르고? 말도 안돼
- 까다롭게 굴지 마
I can take pictures from a jeep
or a water buffalo, if necessary.
지프 같은 곳에 앉아서
사진을 찍을 수도 있어
You're too valuable to the
magazine for us to play around with.
자네같이 귀한 사진사를
그런 위험에 빠뜨릴 순 없어
- I'll send Morgan or Lambert.
- Morgan or Lambert.
- 모건이나 램버트를 보낼 거네
- 모건이나 램버트...
That's fine.
좋아
I get myself half-killed for you,
자네 때문에 이런 꼴이 됐는데
고작 대접이 이거군
And you reward me
by stealing my assignments.
I didn't ask you to stand in
the middle of an automobile racetrack.
자동차 경주 트랙 가운데서
사진 찍으란 소린 안했어
You asked for something
dramatically different.
자넨 파격적인 사진을
찍어 오랬고
- You got it.
- So did you.
- 난 그렇게 했어
- 그랬지
- Goodbye, Jeff.
- Now, wait a minute, Gunnison.
- 잘 있게, 제프
- 잠깐만, 거니슨
You've got to get me out of here.
날 여기서 빼내주게
Six weeks sitting
in a two-room apartment
6주 동안 아파트에 앉아
With nothing to do but look out
the window at the neighbours.
아무런 할 일도 없이
이웃만 내다보고 있어
- Bye, Jeff.
- No, Gunnison, I...
- 잘 있게, 제프
- 거니슨...
이 무료함에서
날 꺼내주지 않으면
If you don't pull me out
of this swamp of boredom,
끔찍한 일을
저지르게 될지도 몰라
I'm gonna do something drastic.
- 어떤 일?
- 결혼해서
- Like what?
- "Like what?" Get married.
아무 데도 갈 수 없게
될지도 몰라
Then I'll never be able to go anywhere.
It's about time you got married,
결혼도 해야지
늙어서 망령나기 전에 말야
Before you turn into
a lonesome and bitter, old man.
Yeach, can't you just see me?
상상이 가나?
Rushing home to a hot apartment
땡하면 집에 들어가서
To listen to the automatic laundry
and the electric dishwasher
세탁기나 돌리고
설거지나 하고
And the garbage disposal
and the nagging wife.
마누라 바가지나 긁히고
살면 보기 좋겠어?
요새 마누라는 바가지를
긁지 않아, 대화를 나누지
Jeff, wives don't nag
any more, they discuss.
Is that so? Is that so?
그래?
Maybe in the high-rent district
they discuss.
비싼 동네에선
대화를 나눌지도 모르지만
In my neighbourhood, they still nag.
이 동네에선
여전히 바가지만 긁던데
Well, you know best.
I'll call you later.
그건 자네가 알겠지
나중에 전화하겠네
Yeach, have some good news
the next time, huh?
그래, 좋은 소식 갖고 걸어줘
안녕하세요?
Good morning. I said, "Good morning!"
안녕하시냐니까요!
Oh, good morning.
네, 안녕하세요
Say, I wouldn't dig so deep
if I were you.
제 생각엔...
화초에 물을 너무 많이
주시는 것 같아요
You're giving them far too much water.
Why don't you shut up?
참견 말아요!
Well!
세상에!
I do declare.
뉴욕에선 훔쳐보는 것에 대해
State sentence
for a peeping tom,
Is six months in the workhouse.
6개월 노동형에 처했던데요
Oh, hello, sweetheart.
어서 와요, 스텔라
그 수용소엔
유리창이 없다더군요
They got no windows in the workhouse.
In the old days, they used to put
your eyes out with a red-hot poker.
옛날엔 쇠꼬챙이로
눈알을 파냈었다구요
Any of those bikini bombshells
you're always watching
비키니 입은 여자가
그렇게도 보기 좋아요?
Worth a red-hot poker?
Oh, dear.
세상에...
We've become a race of Peeping Toms.
모두 엿보는 일에
중독이 되어 가는 것 같아요
What people ought to do
is get outside their own house
가끔은 집 밖으로 나가
기분 전환도 해야 하는데 말이죠
And look in for a change.
Yes, sir. How's that for
a bit of homespun philosophy?
내 개똥철학이 어때요?
Reader's Digest, April 1939.
리더스 다이제스트
1939년 4월호
Well, I only quote from the best.
난 최고만 인용하니까요
You don't have to take
my temperature this morning.
오늘 아침엔
체온 잴 필요 없어요
Quiet. See if you can break 100.
입 다물어요
40도가 넘나 봐야죠
보험회사 간호사 대신에
점쟁이가 될 걸 그랬나봐요
You know, I should have been
a gypsy fortune-teller
Instead of an insurance company nurse.
I got a nose for trouble.
Can smell it ten miles away.
십리 밖의 사고도
느껴진다니까요
You heard of that market crash in "29?
I predicted that.
29년도 주식 폭락 기억하세요?
그걸 예측했었죠
어떻게 알았어요, 스텔라?
Just how did you do that, Stella?
Oh, simple. I was nursing
a director of General Motors.
간단해요, 제네랄 모터스의 부장을
간호하고 있었죠
"Kidney ailment," they said.
"Nerves," I said.
신경과민으로
콩팥에 이상이 왔죠
그래서 생각해 봤죠
Then I asked myself,
'What's General Motors
got to be nervous about?"
뭣 때문에 신경과민일까?
"Overproduction," I says. "Collapse. "
그건 과다 생산이다
그럼 폭락이다
그 부장이 화장실을 들락거릴 때
When General Motors has to go
to the bathroom ten times a day,
The whole country's ready to let go.
시장은 박살났어요
You know, Stella,
in economics, a kidney ailment
콩팥 이상하고 주식 시장은
전혀 관계가 없어요
Has no relationship to the stock market.
- None whatsoever.
- Crashed, didn't it?
그래도 붕괴했잖아요
I can smell trouble
right here in this apartment.
당신도 문제에요
처음엔 다리를 부러뜨리더니
First you smash your leg,
Then you get
to looking out the window,
이젠 봐선 안될
이웃의 사생활을
See things you shouldn't see.
훔쳐보고 있잖아요
Trouble.
문제에요
I can see you in court now
법정에 서 있는 당신 모습이
보이는 듯 해요
Surrounded by a bunch of lawyers
in double-breasted suits.
You're pleading.
당신은 주장하겠죠...
단순한 호기심이었습니다
You say, "Judge,
it was only a bit of innocent fun.
I love my neighbours, like a father. "
전 제 이웃을 사랑합니다
And the judge says,
'Well, congratulations.
그래도 판사는 다나모어에서
3년 노동형에 처할 거예요
You've just given birth
to three years in Dannamora. "
Right now, I'd welcome trouble.
지금 같아선 골 아픈 일이라도
생겼으면 좋겠소
You've got a hormone deficiency.
호르몬 결핍이에요
How can you tell from a thermometer?
체온을 보고 어떻게 알죠?
Those bathing beauties
you've been watching
수영복 입은 미녀를 보고도
Haven't raised your temperature
one degree in a month.
체온이 전혀 오르지 않았어요
Here we go.
시작하죠
One more week.
1주일만 참으면 돼
I think you're right.
당신 말이 맞는 거 같군요
I think there is gonna be
trouble around here.
조만간 문제가 생길 거예요
I knew it.
그럴 줄 알았어요
Ooh. Do you ever heat that stuff?
데워서 하면 안 되나요?
Gives your
circulation something to fight.
혈액순환이 좋아져서
치료에 도움이 될 거예요
- 뭐가 문제죠?
- 리사 프리몬트
- What kind of trouble?
- Lisa Fremont.
You kidding?
She's a beautiful, young girl,
설마! 그렇게 참한 아가씨와...
And you're a reasonably
healthy young man.
젊고 건강한 당신 사이에서요!
- 결혼하고 싶어해요
- 정상이죠
- She expects me to marry her.
- That's normal.
- I don't want to.
- That's abnormal.
- 난 그러고 싶지 않아요
- 비정상이군요
I'm just not ready for marriage.
아직 결혼할 준비가
되어 있지 않아요
Every man's ready for marriage
when the right girl comes along.
좋은 여자만 있으면
준비는 다 된 거예요
Lisa Fremont is the right girl
for any man with half a brain
리사만큼 좋은 규수가
또 어디 있다고 그래요?
Who can get one eye open.
She's alright.
괜찮은 여자죠
- What did you do, have a fight?
- No.
- 그런데, 싸웠나요?
- 아뇨
- Father loading up the shotgun?
- What?
아가씨 아버지가
총을 들고 위협하던가요?
- 뭐요? 스텔라...
- 전에도 있었던 일인 걸요
- Please, Stella.
- It's happened before, you know.
Some of the world's
happiest marriages have
그렇게 결혼해서
행복하게 사는 부부도 있어요
Started "under the gun,'
as you might say.
- No, she's just not the girl for me.
- Yeach, she's only perfect.
내게 어울리는 여자가
아닌 것 같아서 그래요
너무 잘난 여자라 이거군요?
She's too perfect. She's too talented.
너무 완벽하죠
재능도 너무 많고
She's too beautiful.
She's too sophisticated.
너무 예쁘고
너무 세련됐어요
She's too everything, but what I want.
하지만 내겐 안 맞아요
Is what you want
something you can discuss?
뭐가 안 맞는지 말해 줄래요?
What? It's very simple, Stella.
네? 간단해요
리사는 고급이 어울린단 말이에요
She belongs to that rarefied
atmosphere of Park Avenue:
Expensive restaurants
and literary cocktail parties.
비싼 식당에
우아한 칵테일 파티...
People with sense
belong wherever they're put.
현명한 사람은
상황에 잘 대처하죠
Can you imagine her tramping around
the world with a camera bum
아무것도 없는 사진사와
온 세계를 돌아다니는 게
Who never has more than
a week's salary in the bank?
그녀와 어울린다고 생각하세요?
If she was only ordinary.
그녀가 평범하다면
얼마나 좋을까요
You never gonna get married?
그러다간 평생 결혼 못해요
I'll probably get married
one of these days,
아마 하긴 할 거예요
But when I do, it's gonna be
to someone who thinks of life
내 생활을 이해해 주는
사람이라면요
Not just as a new dress
and a lobster dinner
고상한 삶이나 밝히는
사람이면 곤란하죠
And the latest scandal.
I need a woman who's willing to...
Hold it.
난 그러니까...
잡아줘요
Who's willing to go anywhere
and do anything and love it.
어디서 무슨 일을 해도
즐거워 할 여자가 난 필요해요
So the honest thing for me to do
is just call the whole thing off.
Let her find somebody else.
다른 남자를 찾아보라고 할려구요
Yeach, I can hear you now.
알겠어요
"Get out of my life,
you perfectly wonderful woman. "
사랑하니까 헤어지자 이런 건가요?
Look, Mr Jefferies,
I'm not an educated woman,
제프리 씨
전 많이 배운 여자는 아니지만
But I can tell you one thing.
이건 알아요
When a man and a woman see
each other and like each other,
두 남녀가 사랑하면
They ought to come together, wham,
합쳐지는 게 당연해요
Like a couple of taxis on Broadway
한 병에 들어있는 이물질처럼
And not sit around analysing each other
서로를 분석하는 짓은
그만 두고 말이죠
Like two specimens in a bottle.
There's an intelligent way
to approach marriage.
결혼은 이성적으로 생각해야 해요
Intelligence.
이성!
Nothing has caused the human race
so much trouble as intelligence.
그 놈의 이성이
세상을 망친다니까요!
Modern marriage.
현대판 결혼?
- No, we've progressed emotionally.
- Baloney.
- 우린 너무 감정에만 치우쳐 있어요
- 허튼 소리!
Once it was see somebody,
get excited, get married.
옛날엔 사람을 만나
사랑하게 되면 결혼했어요
Now, it's read a lot of books,
요샌 책만 많이 보고
Fence with a lot of four-syllable
words, psychoanalyse each other
쓸데없는 지식만 늘어서는
Until you can't tell the difference
뭐가 진짜로 중요한 지
분간을 못한다니까
Between a petting party
and a civil service exam.
사람마다 감성적인 기준이 달라서...
People have different emotional levels -
When I married Myles, we were both
a couple of maladjusted misfits.
내가 남편과 결혼했을 때
우린 맞는 게 하나도 없었어요
지금도 전혀 맞지 않아요
그래도 재밌게 살고 있어요
We are still maladjusted, and we
have loved every minute of it.
Well, that's fine, Stella.
그만해요, 스텔라
샌드위치나 만들어줘요
Now, would you
fix me a sandwich, please?
Yes, I will. And I'll spread
a little common sense on the bread.
그러죠
빵에 상식을 발라 주겠어요
Lisa's loaded to her fingertips
with love for you.
리사는 당신을 사랑해요
I got two words of advice
for you: Marry her.
충고할 말은 한가지
결혼해요
- She pay you much?
- Oh.
뇌물 먹었소?
There you are.
다 됐습니다
- Here's the key.
- Thank you.
- 여기 열쇠 있습니다
- 고마워요
Well, if you want anything, just ring.
필요한 게 있으면 전화하세요
자기야
Honey.
이리로 와
Come on.
당신을 안고 문을 넘었어
Got to carry you over the threshold.
Window shopper.
고약한 취미군요
How's your leg?
다리는 어때요?
It hurts a little.
약간 아파
- And your stomach?
- Empty as a football.
- 배는요?
- 비어서 뱃가죽이 들러붙었어
애정 생활은?
And your love life?
별로 활동적이지 못해
Not too active.
Anything else bothering you?
그 외 다른 고민은?
누구시죠?
Who are you?
Reading from top to bottom:
처음부터 다 말하자면
Lisa...
리사...
캐롤...
Carol...
Fremont.
프리몬트
Is this the Lisa Fremont who
never wears the same dress twice?
같은 옷은 두 번 입지 않는다는
그 리사 프리몬트?
Only because it's expected of her.
다들 그래주길 원하니까요
It's right off the Paris plane.
파리에서 방금 온 거예요
- Do you think it'll sell?
- That depends on the quote.
- 이게 팔릴까요?
- 말하기에 달렸지
Let's see now.
There's the aeroplane ticket over,
어디 보자
항공표가 달렸고
Import duties, hidden taxes,
관세에다 폭리에다...
- Profit markup
- A steal at $1,100.
1천 1백 달러면
거저나 다름없어요
Eleven hundred?
1천 1백 달러?
주식 시장에 내다 팔아도 되겠다
They ought to list that dress
on the stock exchange.
We sell a dozen a day
in this price range.
하루에 12개도 더 나가는 걸요
Who buys them, tax collectors?
사는 사람이 누구야?
세금쟁이?
이런 옷이라면
돈 주고라도 샀을 거예요
Even if I had to pay,
it would be worth it.
- Just for the occasion.
- Why, is something big going on?
왜, 어디 좋은 데 가려고?
It's going on right here. It's a big night.
여기 오려고요
오늘은 중요한 날이거든요
It's just an old
run-of-the-mill Wednesday.
새털같이 많은
수요일 중 하나잖아
달력에 천지야
The calendar's full of them.
It's opening night of the last depressing...
당신이 지겨운 깁스 풀기
딱 1주일 전이잖아요
...week of L B Jefferies in a cast.
Well, I haven't noticed
a big demand for tickets.
그걸 몰랐네
기념해야 할 날을
That's because I bought out the house.
그래서 선물을 샀어요
You know, this cigarette box
has seen better days.
이 담배 상자는
한 때는 좋았지만...
그건 상해에서 산 거야
그땐 정말 좋았지
I picked that up in Shanghai,
which has also seen better days.
It's cracked and you never use it.
지금은 금이 가서
쓰지도 않잖아요
It's too ornate.
너무 화려했어요
I'm sending up a plain, flat,
그래서 내가 단순한 모양의
은 담배상자를 주문했어요
silver one with your initials.
That's no way to spend
your hard-earned money.
힘들게 번 돈을
그런 데 쓰면 되나
그러고 싶었는 걸요
I wanted to.
21 식당에서 이번 주일을
시작하는 게 어때요?
What would you think of
starting off with dinner at "21 "?
You have, perhaps,
an ambulance downstairs?
아래층에 앰뷸런스 불러놨어?
No, better than that: "21 ".
더 좋은 생각을 했죠
기다려줘서 고마워요, 칼
부엌은 저쪽이에요
Thank you for waiting, Carl.
The kitchen's right there on the left.
I'll take the wine.
포도주는 이리 주세요
- 안녕하십니까, 제프리 씨
- 칼
- Good evening, Mr Jefferies.
- Carl.
Just put everything
in the oven, Carl, on low.
전부 오븐에 넣어놔요
- 이제 포도주를 따죠
- 좋아
- Let's open the wine now.
- Alright.
- 몬트라쳇이에요
- 한잔 가득 따라 줘
- It's a Montrachet.
- A great big glassful.
There's a corkscrew right over there.
코르크 따개는 저쪽에 있어
내가 할께
Here, I'll do it.
- Big enough?
- Yeach, they're fine.
- 이 정도 크기면 돼요?
- 좋아
깁스를 하고 있는 것처럼
따분한 일이 또 있을까
I can't think of anything more
boring or tiresome
Than what you've been through
and the last week must be the hardest.
아마도 지난 주가
제일 힘들었을 거예요
- 제가 하죠
- 그래
Alright. Yeach, I want to get
this thing off and get moving.
어서 풀고 돌아다니고 싶어
이번 주를 평생 잊지 못할
시간으로 만들어 줄께요
Well, I'm going to make this
a week you'll never forget.
Fine, thanks.
고마워
잠깐만요, 칼
Just a minute, Carl.
- This will take care of the taxi.
- Thank you, Miss Fremont.
- 택시비 하세요
- 감사합니다, 프리몬트 양
- Have a pleasant dinner, Mr Jefferies.
- Alright, Good night.
- 저녁 맛있게 드십시오, 제프리 씨
- 잘 가게
Good night.
안녕히 가세요
What a day I've had.
정말 바쁜 하루였어요
- Are you tired?
- Not a bit.
- 피곤해?
- 전혀요
I was all morning in a meeting,
아침 내내 판매 회의에 들어갔다가
Then I had to dash to the Waldorf
for a quick drink with Madam Dufrene,
파리의 최신 유행을 알아 온
Who's just over from Paris
with some spy reports.
듀프린 여사와 한잔하고
Then I had to go to "21" and have lunch
with the Harper's Bazaar people.
21에 가서
하퍼 잡지사 사람과 점심하고
그 때 저녁 주문을 했죠
That's when I ordered dinner.
그 다음에
가을 패션쇼를 보고
Then I had two fall showings
20 blocks apart.
리랜드와 헤이워드 부인과
칵테일 한잔하고
Then I had to have a cocktail
with Leland and Slim Hayward.
We're trying to get his new show.
그리고 집에 가서
옷 갈아입고 온 거예요
Then I had to dash back and change.
Well, now, tell me,
what was Mrs Hayward wearing?
헤이워드 부인은 뭘 입고 있었지?
- She looked wonderfully cool.
- She didn't, did she?
정말 멋지게 입었어요
She had on the most divine
Italian hand-printed -
이탈리아제 모슬린이
환상적이었어요
- Oh, Italian?
- Oh, you.
이탈리아? 이탈리아제라...
상상이 가는군
- Italian. Imagine.
- To think I planted three nice items
오늘 당신에 대해
세 번이나 언급 했었죠
- In the columns about you today.
- You did?
그랬어?
- You can't buy that kind of publicity.
- I know.
- 그만한 광고 효과도 없을 걸요
- 알아
Someday you may want to
open up a studio of your own here.
언젠간 당신의 스튜디오를
열 수도 있잖아요
How would I run it from, say, Pakistan?
세계를 돌아다니면서
운영을 할 수 있을까?
제프...
Jeff...
Isn't it time you came home?
You could pick your assignment.
정착하는 게 어때요?
자리를 잡을 수 있으면요
원하는 자리가 있으면
- I wish there was one I wanted.
- Make the one you want.
- 원하는 걸 만들어요
- 잡지사를 떠나란 말이야?
- You mean leave the magazine?
- Yes.
- 그래요
- 뭣 때문에?
- For what?
- For yourself and me.
당신과 절 위해서요
I could get you a dozen
assignments tomorrow:
당신 일거리는 얼마든지 있어요
Fashions, portraits.
패션 사진이나 초상화...
- Now, don't laugh. I could do it.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
- 웃지 말아요, 난 할 수 있어요
- 난 그게 두려워
Can you see me driving down
to the fashion salon in a jeep
내가 지프를 타고
전투화를 신고
Wearing combat boots and a three-day
beard? Wouldn't that make a hit?
3일 기른 수염을 하고
고급 의상실에 가는 게 상상이 가?
I could see you looking
very handsome and successful
어두운 청색 양복을 입으면
정말 멋질 거예요
In a dark blue, flannel suit.
Let's stop talking nonsense, shall we?
말도 안 되는 얘긴
그만 하도록 하지
Guess I'd better
start setting up for dinner.
그만 저녁 준비를 할께요
Miss Lonelyhearts.
미스 고독
최소한 당신은 저런 건
걱정 안 해도 될 거야
At least that's something
you'll never have to worry about.
그래요?
Oh?
You can see my apartment from here,
all the way up on 63rd Street?
여기서 내가 사는
아파트도 보이나요?
No, not exactly,
but we have a little apartment here
그렇지 않지만
여기도 당신 집만큼
That's probably as popular as yours.
인기 있는 곳이 있어
You remember, of course,
Miss Torso, the ballet dancer?
토르소 양 기억해?
발레 댄서 말야
She's like a queen bee
with her pick of the drones.
수많은 일벌을 거느린
여왕벌 같은 여자야
I'd say she's
doing a woman's hardest job.
늑대를 물리치느라 힘들겠군요
Juggling wolves.
Thank you.
고마워
Well, she picked the most
prosperous-looking one.
제일 잘 나갈 것 같은
남자를 고르면 되겠네
She's not in love with him...
Or any of them.
저 중엔 사랑하는
남자가 없군요
Oh, how can you tell that from here?
그걸 어떻게 알지?
You said it resembled
my apartment, didn't you?
내가 사는 집과
비슷하다고 하지 않았나요?
I hope they're cooked this time.
제 시간에 식사 좀
했으면 좋겠어요
이 아름다운 음악은
어디서 들려오는 거죠?
Where's that
wonderful music coming from?
Some songwriter over there
in the studio apartment.
건너편에 작곡가가 살아
Well...
아마...
혼자 살지
He lives alone.
아마 결혼생활이 불행했나봐
Probably had a very unhappy marriage.
Oh, it's enchanting.
너무 아름다워요
It's almost as if it were
being written especially for us.
마치 우리 둘을 위해
만든 노래 같아요
Hm. No wonder he's having
so much trouble with it.
그래서 그렇게 고생을 했군
At least you can't say
the dinner isn't right.
설마 저녁이
별로란 얘긴 아니겠죠?
Lisa...
It's perfect.
리사, 완벽해
As always.
언제나처럼
There can't be that much difference
between people and the way they live.
사람 사는 건 다 똑같아요
We all eat, talk, drink,
laugh, wear clothes.
먹고 떠들고 웃고 입고
Well, now look -
이것 봐...
If you're saying all this because
you don't want to tell me the truth,
차라리 말 못할 사정이 있거나
Because you're hiding something from
me, then maybe I can understand.
나한테 숨기는 게 있어서
그런 거라면 이해하겠어요
I'm not hiding anything. It's just that -
- 그런 건 없어
- 말도 안 돼요
It doesn't make sense.
What's so different about it here
from there or anyplace you go
여기랑 당신이 가는 곳이랑
다를 게 뭐가 있어요
That one person couldn't live
in both places just as easily?
사람 사는 게 똑같죠
그렇지 않아
내 설명을 들어봐
Some people can.
Now, if you'll just let me -
What is it but travelling from
one place to another taking pictures?
이곳 저곳 다니면서
사진 찍고
It's like being a tourist
on an endless vacation.
끝없는 여행 같은 거죠
당신 의견이 그렇겠지
그럴만 해
OK. That's your opinion.
You're entitled to it.
- Now, let me give you my side.
- It's ridiculous to say
내 말 좀 들어봐
소수의 사람만 그럴 수
있다는 건 언어도단이에요
That it can only be done by a special,
private little group of anointed people.
I made a simple statement,
a true statement,
난 솔직히 말한 거야
But I can back it up if you'll just
shut up for a minute.
잠깐, 내 말 좀 들어봐!
If your opinion is as rude as your manner,
태도를 봐선
당신 의견은 들으나 마나에요
...I don't think I care to hear it.
그만 진정해
Oh, come on now. Simmer down.
난 여기가 안 맞고
당신은 저기가 안 맞고!
I can't fit in here. You can't fit in there.
According to you, people
should be born, live and die
그렇다면 태어난 곳에서
평생 살다 죽어야겠네요!
- On the same spot!
- Shut up!
그만 좀 해!
- Did you ever eat fish heads and rice?
- Of course not.
생선 머리와
쌀밥 먹어본 적 있어?
물론 없죠
Well, you might have to
if you went with me.
나랑 함께 가면
먹어야 할지도 몰라
Did you ever try to keep warm
in a C-54 at 15,000 feet,
고도 15,000피트
영하 20도 되는 곳에서
잠 자본 적 있어?
20 degrees below zero?
Oh, I do it all the time,
점심 먹고 시간 있을 때마다
하는 일이죠
Whenever I have
a few minutes after lunch.
Did you ever get shot at? Run over?
총에 맞아 봤어?
차에 치인 적은?
Did you ever get sandbagged
한밤중에 샌드백처럼
얻어 터져봤어?
Because somebody got unfavourable
publicity from your camera?
Did you ever... Those high heels,
they'll be great in the jungle.
하이힐에 6온스 짜리 속옷 입고
And the nylons
and those six-ounce lingerie.
잘도 정글을 다니겠다
- Three.
- Alright, three.
- 3온스에요
- 좋아, 3온스
They'll make a big hit in Finland,
just before you freeze to death.
핀란드에 가면
얼어죽기 꼭 알맞지
Well, if there's one thing I know,
it's how to wear the proper clothes.
옷 하나만은 계절에 맞게
잘 챙겨 입어요
Yeach, yeach.
그래, 브라질에 가서
비옷을 찾아보시지
Well, try and find a raincoat in Brazil,
even when it isn't raining.
이 일은 가방 하나
달랑 들고 떠나야 해
Lisa, in this job you carry one suitcase.
Your home
is the available transportation.
차 안이 집이고
You don't sleep very much.
You bathe less.
잠도 제대로 못 자고
목욕도 자주 못해
And sometimes the food that you eat
쳐다보기도 싫은 음식을
먹어야 할 때도 있어
Is made from things that you couldn't
even look at when they're alive.
날 겁주려고 과장해서
말하지 않아도 돼요
Jeff, you don't have to be deliberately
repulsive just to impress me I'm wrong.
Deliberately repulsive?
I'm trying to make it sound good.
과장해서 얘기한다고?
난 봐주면서 얘기한 건데?
You just have to face it, Lisa,
you're not meant for that kind of a life.
당신은 이런 생활에 맞지 않아
맞는 사람이 별로 없지
Few people are.
- You're too stubborn to argue with.
- I'm not stubborn. I'm just truthful.
말이 통하는 고집이래야지
고집이 아니라
사실대로 말한 거야
I know, a lesser man would have
told me it was one long holiday,
나도 휴가라는 환상은
갖고 있지 않아요
And I would have awakened
to a rude disillusionment.
Well, now, wait a minute.
잠깐만
If you want to get vicious on this thing,
내 말이 심했다면
좋은 말로 해줄 수도 있어
I'd be happy to accommodate you.
No, I don't particularly want that.
아뇨, 그럴 필요 없어요
결국 당신이 여기 있을 수도
내가 따라 갈 수도 없다구요?
So that's it?
You won't stay here,
and I can't go with you.
It would be the wrong thing.
잘못된 거니까
You don't think either one
of us could ever change?
우리 둘 중 하나가
변할 수도 없을까요?
Right now it doesn't seem so.
지금으로선 그럴 것 같지 않아
I- I'm in love with you.
난 당신을 사랑해요
직업이 뭐든 상관없어요
I don't care what you do for a living.
I'd like to be part of it somehow.
난 당신의 한 부분이
되고 싶어요
사랑하는 당신의 일을
따라갈 수 없다면
It's deflating to find out
the only way I can be part of it,
Is to take out a subscription
to your magazine.
절망뿐이에요
난 내가 생각했던 여자가
못되는 모양이에요
I guess I'm not the girl I thought I was.
There's nothing wrong with you, Lisa.
당신은 잘못 없어, 리사
You've got this town
in the palm of your hand.
세계가 당신 손아귀에 있잖아
Not quite, it seems.
그렇지 않아요
Goodbye, Jeff.
잘 있어요, 제프
You mean good night.
잘 자란 말이겠지
- I mean what I said.
- Well, Lisa...
- 진심이에요
- 리사...
Couldn't we just...
그냥...
Keep things status quo?
지금 이 상태로 지내면 안될까?
Without any future?
미래도 없이요?
Well, when am I gonna see you again?
언제 다시 만날 수 있지?
Not for a long time.
오랫동안은 못 볼 거예요
At least...
Not until tomorrow night.
최소한 내일 저녁까진 안 돼요
Hey! Rain.
비다!
Grab that. Wait, I'll get the clock.
잡아봐, 잠깐만
시계는 내가 챙길께
Oh, no!
Pull it.
끌어당겨봐
Pull on it. Let me do it.
끌어당기라니까
들어가
In you go.
너무 늦었어요
No, you can't come in.
It's much too late.
안돼요
No, not now.
No, I said good night.
가라고 했잖아요
제목이 뭐죠?
What's that supposed to be, ma'am?
It's called hunger.
굶주림이요
You'd think the rain
would have cooled things off.
비가 오면
더위가 가실 줄 알았는데
- All it did was make the heat wet.
- Ahh, that's it.
- 끈적거리기만 하네요
- 거기...
That's stiff right there. Right there.
거기가 결려요
휠체어에서 자지 말고
침대에서 자요
The insurance company
would be much happier
If you'd sleep in bed at night
instead of in that wheelchair.
- 어떻게 알았죠?
- 눈이 충혈된 걸 보니
- How do you know?
- Eyes are all bloodshot.
Must have been watching
out that window for hours.
몇 시간 동안
밖만 내다보고 있었겠죠
그랬어요
Yeach, I was.
What are you gonna do
if one of them catches you?
그러다 들키면
어떡하려고 그래요?
It depends which one.
Miss Torso, for example -
누구냐에 따라 다르죠
저 육체파 아가씨라면...
You keep your mind off her.
그 여잔 잊어요
잘 먹고 잘 마시는
명랑한 처녀일 거예요
She sure is the
'eat, drink and be merry" girl.
Yeach, she'll wind up fat,
alcoholic and miserable.
나중에 알코올 중독
뚱보가 될 테니 두고 봐요
Yeach.
그러고 보니 미스 고독이
Speaking of misery,
poor Miss Lonelyhearts.
She drank herself to sleep again, alone.
자기 전 또 술을 마시더군요
불쌍한 사람, 언젠간 행복을
찾을 날이 있겠죠
Poor soul. Maybe one day
she'll find her happiness.
Yeach, and some man will lose his.
한 남자는 불행해지고 말이죠
Isn't there anybody in the
neighbourhood
그녀 방을 볼 수 있는 아파트가
여기 말고 없나요?
Who could cast an eye in her direction?
Well...
모르겠어요
저 외판원이 머지 않아
혼자가 될 텐데
It might just be that the salesman
will be available soon.
Oh, him and his wife splitting up?
부인과 헤어지나요?
I just can't figure it.
잘 모르겠어요
He went out several times
last night in the rain,
어젯밤 비가 오는데 가방을 들고
- Carrying his sample case.
- Well, he's a salesman, isn't he?
- 수 차례 나갔다 오더군요
- 외판원이라면서요?
What would he be selling
at three o'clock in the morning?
새벽 3시에 뭘 팔러 나갔을까요?
Flashlights.
Luminous dials for watches.
전지, 시계에 필요한 거
House numbers that light up.
또는 불이 켜지는 집주소라든가
그렇지 않을 걸요
I don't think so.
그렇지 않을 거예요
I think he was taking
something out of the apartment.
집에서 뭔가를
내가는 것 같았어요
Uh-huh. His personal effects.
소지품이었겠죠
여자한테서 도망치려 하는군요
비겁한 놈
He's gonna run out on her, the coward.
가끔은 도망치는 게
나을 때도 있죠
Yeach. Sometimes it's worse
to stay than it is to run.
Yeach, well, it takes a particularly low
type of man to do a thing like that.
도망치는 남자는
저질 중에 저질이에요
How about this morning?
오늘 아침엔 어땠어요?
Any further developments?
발전이 있었어요?
아뇨, 아침 내내 커튼이 쳐있었어요
The shades are all drawn
in the apartment.
- In this heat?
- Yeach.
이런 더위에?
Well, they're up now.
열었는데요
- Get back! Get back.
- Where do you want me to go?
- 물러서요!
- 어디로 가란 말인가요?
- Come on, get out of sight.
- What's the matter?
- 보이지 않게 물러서요!
- 왜 그래요?
That salesman's looking out of
his window. You see?
외판원이 창 밖을 보고 있어요
Get back! He'll see you.
물러서요!
I'm not shy. I've been looked at before.
난 숨길 게 없어요
볼 테면 보라죠 뭐
That's no ordinary look.
예사로운 모습이 아니에요
누군가 볼까봐
두려워하는 모습이에요
That's the kind of look a man gives
When he's afraid somebody
might be watching him.
Get away from there.
거기서 나오지 못해
어서 나와!
He'll be after you.
Go on, into the house.
Into the house. Shoo, shoo.
Goodbye, Mr Jefferies.
See you tomorrow.
잘 있어요, 제프리 씨
내일 봐요
- And don't sleep in that chair again.
- Uh-huh.
제발 의자에서 자지 말아요
대답만 잘하지
"Uh-huh. Uh-huh. "
Great conversationalist.
스텔라...
Stella...
Take those binoculars out
and bring them here, will you?
가방 안에서 쌍안경 좀
가져다 줄래요?
골 아픈 일이 생길 줄 알았지
Trouble.
I can smell it.
I'll be glad when they crack
that cast, and I can get outta here.
어서 깁스를 풀어야
이 꼴을 다시 안 볼 텐데
How far does a girl have to go...
얼마나 새침을 떨어야
관심을 가져줄 거예요?
...before you'll notice her?
Well, if she's pretty enough,
she doesn't have to go anywhere.
당신은 예쁘니까
그럴 필요 없어
She just has to "be. '
- 그냥 있어주면 돼
- 그런가요?
Well, ain't I?
Pay attention to me.
그래도 나한테 신경 좀 써줘요
I'm not exactly
on the other side of the room.
쓰고 있잖아
내가 어디 다른 곳에 있어?
Your mind is... And when I
want a man, I want all of him.
마음은 딴 데 있어요
난 몸도 마음도 다 원해요
Don't you ever have any problems?
고민 해본 적 있어?
I have one now.
지금 하고 있어요
So do I.
나도 그래
Tell me about it.
말해봐요
Why?
왜?
Why would a man leave
his apartment three times
어떤 남자가 자기 집을 세 번이나
들락날락한 이유가 뭘까?
그것도 비 오는 새벽에
가방을 들고 말야
On a rainy night with a suitcase,
and come back three times?
He likes the way his wife
welcomes him home.
부인이 반갑게 맞아 주나보죠
아니, 이 남자 부인은 안 그래
No, no. Not this salesman's wife.
And why didn't he go to work today?
오늘은 그 남자가
왜 출근을 안 했지?
Homework. It's more interesting.
집에서 일하나 보죠
흥미롭네요
What's interesting about a butcher knife
식칼과 작은 톱을
신문지에 싼 일도 흥미로워?
And a small saw
Wrapped in newspaper?
Nothing, thank heaven.
아뇨, 그럴 수가
Why hasn't he been
in his wife's bedroom all day?
왜 부인의 침실에
하루종일 들어가지 않는 거지?
I wouldn't dare answer that.
대답을 못 하겠군요
Well, listen. I'll answer it, Lisa.
내가 대답해 주지
뭔가 끔찍한 일이 일어난 거야
There's something terribly wrong.
- And I'm afraid it's with me.
- What do you think?
- 내 생각이 맞을까봐 두렵군요
- 무슨 생각?
입을 열기도 두려워요
Something too frightful to utter.
He went out a few minutes
ago in his undershirt, hasn't come back.
속옷 바람으로 나갔는데
아직 돌아오지 않았어
말로 옮기기는 끔찍하지만
That would be a terrible job to tackle.
Just how would you start
to cut up a human body?
사람 시체를
어떻게 토막내는 걸까?
솔직히 말해서
당신이 무서워요
Jeff, I'll be honest with you.
You're beginning to scare me.
내 말 들었어요?
Jeff, did you hear what I said?
You're beginning to scare -
- 무섭다구요
- 쉿, 돌아왔어!
Shh! He's coming back!
- Jeff, if you could only see yourself!
- What's the matter?
- 제프, 당신 모습을 봐요!
- 내가 어때서?
Sitting around looking out of the
window to kill time is one thing,
앉아서 밖을 내다보며
소일하는 건 좋아요
But doing it the way
you are with binoculars
하지만 쌍안경으로 보면서
비약하는 건 병이에요
And wild opinions about every...
...little thing you see is diseased!
Do you think I consider it recreation?
내가 재미로 이러는 줄 알아?
I don't know what you consider it,
뭔지 모르지만
But if you don't stop it,
I'm getting out of here.
그만하지 않으면 난 가겠어요
- What's the
- What is it you're looking for?
찾는 게 뭐에요?
I just want to find out what's
the matter with the salesman's wife.
저 남자의 부인이 어떻게 됐나
알고 싶을 뿐이야
Does that make me
sound like a madman?
그게 미친 짓일까?
What makes you think there's
something the matter with her?
왜 부인에게 사고가
생겼다고 생각하는 거죠?
그녀는 병자라서 항상 보살피는
사람이 있어야 된단 말야
A lot of things. She's an invalid.
She demands constant care.
Yet not the husband or anybody else
has been in to see her all day. Why?
그런데 하루종일 그녀 방에
들어가는 사람이 없었어
- Maybe she died.
- Where's the doctor?
- 죽었나보죠
- 그럼 의사는, 장의사는 어딨어?
Where's the undertaker?
She could be sleeping, under sedatives.
그럼, 수면제 먹고 자고 있나보죠
남편이 들어왔어요
이젠 볼 거 없어요
He's in there now.
There's nothing to see.
뭔가가 있어
There is something.
I've seen it through that window.
I've seen bickering and family quarrels
그 동안 내내
부부싸움이 그치질 않았어
한밤중에 외출하고
And mysterious trips at night
And knives and saws and rope.
식칼에 톱에 로프까지...
Now, since last evening, not a sign
of the wife. Tell me where she is.
또 어젯밤부턴 부인이 보이질 않아
부인은 어디서 뭘 하는 거지?
- I don't know.
- What's she doing?
모르겠어요
그게 무슨 상관이에요
Maybe he's leaving his wife.
I don't know. I don't care!
Lots of people have knives and saws
and ropes around their houses.
집에 식칼과 톱
로프를 가진 사람은 많아요
하루종일 부인과 말 한 마디
하지 않는 남편도 많고요
And lots of men don't speak
to their wives all day.
Lots of wives nag and
men hate them and trouble starts,
부부싸움을 하는
부부도 굉장히 많아요
그들 중 살인하는 사람은
아주 극소수라구요!
But few of them end up in murder,
if that's what you're thinking.
그 말 하기가 그렇게 힘들었어?
It's pretty hard for you to keep
away from that word, isn't it?
You could see all that he did,
couldn't you?
그 사람 행동을
전부 보고 있었죠?
- Of course, I
- You could see co?the shades were up
그가 복도를 내려가
뒤뜰에 나온 것도 봤죠?
And he walked along the corridor
and the street and the backyard.
물론 다 봤지
I've seen him -
살인자라면 그런 걸 보게 놔뒀겠어요?
Jeff, do you think a murderer
would let you see all that?
That he wouldn't pull the shades
down and hide behind them?
커튼을 쳐서
그 뒤에 숨지 않았을까요?
그러니까 교활한 놈이지
He's being clever. He's being nonchalant.
And that's
where you're not bring clever.
당신은 그만큼 교활하지 않구요?
A murderer would never parade
his crime in front of an open window.
살인자는 자신의 범행을
창가에서 저지르지 않아요
Why not?
왜지?
커튼 뒤에서 더 사악한 일이
벌어지고 있으니까요
For all you know, there's
something sinister going on there.
Where? Oh.
어디서?
No comment.
할 말이 없군
Let's start
from the beginning again, Jeff.
처음부터 다시 말해줘요
Tell me everything you saw
다 말해줘요
And what you think it means.
당신이 보고 생각한 모든 것을
Yeach?
네?
우편함에 라스 쏜월드 부부라고
써있었어요
"The name on the second floor
Rear mail box reads,
'Mr and Mrs Lars'."
"That's L-a-r-s. "
L-a-r-s
라스 쏜월드
"Lars Thorwald. "
아파트 번호는?
What's the number of the apartment?
"125 West Ninth Street. "
125호, 서쪽 9번 가
수고했어
Thank you, dear.
"OK, chief.
What's my next assignment?"
다음 임무는 뭐죠?
집에 가
Just go home.
좋아요
그 자는 지금 뭐하고 있어요?
'Alright, but what's he doing now?"
불 끄고 거실에 앉아 있어
He's just sitting
in the living room in the dark.
Hasn't gone near the bedroom.
침실 근처엔 가지 않았어
Now you go home
and get some sleep. Good night.
이제 그만 집에 가서 자
"Good night. "
잘 자요
"What's it about, Jeff?"
무슨 일인가, 제프?
전화로는 말할 수 없네
Look, Doyle,
I can't tell you over the phone.
- 와서 직접 보도록 해
- 뭔데 그래?
You have to be here
and see the whole set-up.
It's probably nothing.
It's just a little neighbourhood murder.
별 일 아니야
이웃에 살인 사건이 생긴 것 같아서
- "Did you say murder?"
- Yes, as a matter of fact, I did.
- 살인이라고 했나?
- 그래, 살인이라고 했네
"Oh, come now. "
오, 저런...
자네 일을 덜어주려고 말이지
My only thought was throwing a little
business your way, that's all.
I figured a detective would jump at
the chance of something to detect.
형사는 사건이 생기면
뛰어오는 줄 알았는데
- 근무 중이 아니야
- 뭐라구?
- "I'm not working. "
- What?
"This happens to be my day off. "
쉬는 날이라구
I usually took my best pictures
on my day off.
난 쉬는 날
꼭 좋은 사진을 찍게 되던 걸
- 내가 잠깐 들를께
- 좋아, 도일, 서둘러 주게
- "I'll drop by. "
- OK, Doyle. As soon as you can.
착하기도 하셔라, 스텔라
Bless your heart, Stella.
이렇게 반가울 수가 없습니다
Gee whiz, look at this.
I can't tell you
what a welcome sight this is.
No wonder your husband still loves you.
남편의 사랑을 받는 게
우연이 아니었군요
경찰?
- The police.
- What?
- You called the police.
- Well, not exactly.
경찰에 신고했군요
아직 신고는 안 했어요
오래된 친구에요
Not an official call.
It's an old friend of mine.
오래된 친구요
An old, ornery friend of mine.
어디서 토막냈을까요?
Just where do you suppose
he cut her up?
Of course. The bathtub.
물론 목욕탕이겠군요!
That's the only place where
he could have washed away the blood.
그래야 피를 씻어내기 좋으니까요
He better get that trunk out
of there before it starts to leak.
새기 전에 가방을
들어내는 게 좋을 텐데
Harry?
해리?
Look, look, Mr Jefferies.
봐요, 제프리 씨!
I thought Doyle would be here
by the time the trunk left,
가방이 나가기 전에
도일이 올 줄 알았는데
Or I'd have called the police.
Now we're gonna lose it.
이러다 놓치겠어요
- Hold everything.
- Don't do anything foolish.
- 기다려요
- 바보 같은 짓 말아요
I'm just gonna get the name
off that freight truck.
짐 실은 트럭 이름을 알아 올께요
I'll keep an eye on the alley.
난 골목을 보고 있을께요
Long distance.
장거리 전화로군
살인 장면이나 시체를 보지도 않고
어떻게 살인이 일어난 걸 알지?
You didn't see the killing or the body.
How do you know there was a murder?
Because everything this fellow's done
has been suspicious:
이 남자 행동이 수상쩍었으니까
Trips at night in the rain,
knives and saws and trunks with rope,
비 오는 날 한밤중에 외출하고
식칼에 톱에 로프로 싼 가방에
부인도 보이질 않고 말이야
And now this wife
that isn't there any more.
I admit it all has a mysterious sound.
모든 게 의심스럽군
It could be any number of things.
Murder's the least possible.
여러 가지 가능성이 있지만
살인일 가능성은 거의 없어
Doyle, don't tell me
he's an unemployed magician,
설마 내가 착각한 거라고
말하려는 건 아니겠지?
Amusing the neighbourhood
with his sleight of hand.
Don't tell me that.
It's too obvious and stupid
a way to commit murder.
남들이 보는 데서 살인하는
바보가 어딨겠나?
In full view of 50 windows?
Then sit there smoking a cigar,
waiting for the police to pick him up.
그리곤 경찰이 올 때까지
태연히 기다린다?
Alright, officer, do your duty.
Go over and pick him up.
경찰 나리
가서 저 놈을 체포하라구요!
제프, 강력 사건은 그런 게 아니야
Jeff, you've got a lot
to learn about homicide.
Why, morons have committed
murder so shrewdly,
불 보듯 뻔한 살인 사건도
다 절차가 있는 법이야
It's taken a hundred trained
police minds to catch them.
That salesman wouldn't just
knock his wife off after dinner
저 판매원이 부인을 죽이고
가방에 넣었단 말이야?
And toss her in the trunk
and put her in storage.
I'll bet it's been done.
틀림없어
살인자는 열에 아홉은 겁에 질리지
Most everything's been done...
Under panic.
This is a thousand-to-one shot.
He's still sitting around the apartment.
That man's not panicked.
그런데 저 남자는
전혀 겁에 질리지 않았어
내가 헛 것을 봤단 말인가?
You think I made all this up?
Well, I think you saw something
오해를 한 거라고 해두세
There's probably
a very simple explanation for.
- For instance?
- Wife took a trip.
- 예를 들면?
- 부인은 여행을 떠났다
부인은 아파서
침대에 누워 있었어
His wife was sick in bed.
Yeach, so you told me.
그래, 그랬었지
Well, Jeff, I've got to run along.
난 그만 가봐야겠네
I won't report this to the department.
Let me poke into it a little on my own.
이 일은 보고하지 않겠네
내가 따로 알아보지
No sense in your getting
a lot of ridiculous publicity.
자네 만한 유명인사면 시끄러워져
고마워
Thank you.
We know the wife is gone,
so I'll see if I can find out where.
부인이 어디 간 것 같으니까
어디 갔는지 알아볼께
Do that.
그래 주게
You had any headaches lately?
- 최근에 두통이 있지 않았나?
- 자네가 오기 전엔 없었어
Not till you showed up.
오해가 풀리면 사라질 거야
그럼 또 보세
It will wear off,
along with the hallucinations.
See you around.
Get along.
저리 가
6개월 전세를 들었는데
He has a six months" lease.
Used up a little more than
five and a half months of it.
5개월 반이 지났대
He's quiet,
drinks, but not to drunkenness.
조용하고 술은 마시지만
지나친 정도는 아니고
Pays his bills promptly
with money earned
공과금도 착실히 내고
보석 판매를 한다고 하더군
As a costume jewellery salesman:
wholesale.
Kept to himself. No neighbours
got close to him or his wife.
친하게 지내는 이웃은
한 사람도 없었어
Yeach, well, I think
they missed their chance with her.
그래, 부인하고 친할 기회는
영영 사라졌지
She never left the apartment,
until yesterday morning.
어제 아침까진 부인은
아파트를 떠난 적이 한번도 없었어
- What time?
- 6:00am.
- 몇 시에 떠났는데?
- 아침 6시
6:00am.
아침 6시
I think that's
about the time I fell asleep.
내가 잠들었을 시간이로군
Too bad.
쏜월드 부부는 그 시간에 나왔어
Thorwalds were leaving
their apartment at just that time.
맥 빠지지?
Feel a little foolish?
아니, 아직 아니야
No, not yet.
- How's your wife?
- Oh, she's fine.
- 부인은 어떤가?
- 잘 있어
그때 나왔다고 누가 그래?
Who said they left then?
- W-Who left where?
- The Thorwalds, at 6:00am.
- 누가 어딜 나와?
- 쏜월드 부부가 아침 6시에 말야
Oh, the building superintendent
and two tenants.
건물 수위와 주민 2명
Flat statements, no hesitation.
They jived with the letter.
서슴없이 말하던데
Thorwalds were on their way
to the railroad station.
쏜월드 부부가 기차역에
가는 길이라고 하더래
그걸 어떻게 알았지?
Well, now, Tom, how could
anybody possibly guess that?
What, did they have signs
on their luggage saying,
가방에 기차표라도 붙어 있었대?
'Grand Central, or bust'?
The superintendent
met Thorwald on his way back.
수위가 돌아오는
쏜월드를 만났는데
Thorwald told him that he'd put
his wife on a train to the country.
부인을 기차에 태워주고
오는 길이라더래
I see. I'd say this is a pretty
convenient guy, this superintendent.
그 수위라는 사람 못 믿어
Have you checked
his bank statements lately?
은행 잔고 확인해 봤어?
- Huh?
- Well, what good's his information?
그게 무슨 도움이 돼?
살인자의 입에서 나온 말을
그대로 옮긴 것뿐인 걸
It's a secondhand version of
an unsupported story by the murderer.
아무도 부인이 기차에 타는 걸
직접 보진 못했잖아
Now did anybody actually see
the wife get on the train?
부인이 살해됐다고 자네가
주장해서 지금까지 온 거야
I hate to remind you,
But this all started because
you said she was murdered.
자네를 포함해서 살인 장면을
목격한 사람이 있나?
Now, did anyone, including you,
actually see her murdered?
What are you doing?
사건을 해결하려는 거야
사람 바보 만들려는 거야?
Are you interested in solving
this case or making me look foolish?
Well, if possible, both.
가능하다면 둘 다 하고 싶은데
그럼 제대로 해봐
쏜월드의 집을 수색하면
Then do a good job of it.
Go over there and search
Thorwald's apartment.
It must be knee-deep in evidence.
증거가 나올 걸
I can't do that.
그럴 수 없어
I don't mean right now,
but when he goes out for a drink,
지금 당장 하라는 게 아니라
Or a paper, or something.
What he doesn't know won't hurt him.
없을 때 살짝 하란 말이야
I can't do that even if he isn't there.
없을 때라도 수색은 못해
What's he...
그 남자 경찰서에
큰 빽이라도 있는 거야?
Does he have a courtesy card from
the police department or something?
Now don't get me mad.
화나게 하지 마
Not even a detective can walk
into an apartment and search it.
형사라도 아무 집이나 들어가
수색할 순 없어
If I were caught in there, they'd
have my badge within ten minutes.
들키기라도 하면
난 그 자리에서 해고야
Make sure
you don't get caught, that's all.
그럼 들키지만 않으면 될 거 아니야
If you find something,
you've got a murderer,
살인범을 잡기만 하면
사소한 규칙 위반은 괜찮을 걸
And they don't care about
a couple of house rules.
If you don't find anything,
the fellow's clear.
아무것도 나오지 않으면
혐의를 벗는 거고
At the risk of sounding stuffy,
고지식하게 들리겠지만
I'd like to remind you
of the Constitution and the phrase,
수색영장이란 소리 들어봤나?
'search warrant issued by a judge "
who knows the Bill of Rights verbatim.
증거가 있어야
판사가 내어주는 영장 말이야
- He must ask for evidence.
- Give him evidence.
- 증거를 주면 될 거 아니야
- 이렇게 말할까?
판사님, 아마추어 탐정을 하는
친구가 하나 있는데요
Yeach, I can hear myself,
"Your Honour, I have a friend
who's an amateur sleuth. "
멀쩡히 저녁을 먹고는
"The other night, after
having a heavy dinner, he... "
내 앞에서 법을 위반했는데
어떻게 하면 좋을까요?
He'd throw the New York State
penal code in my face,
And there's six volumes.
By tomorrow morning there
may not be any evidence left
내일 아침이면
증거가 전부 사라질 거야
Over in that apartment, you know that.
It's a detective's nightmare.
형사들이 제일 두려워하는 일이지
What do you need
before you can search?
영장을 얻으려면 뭐가 필요해?
Tell me now, what do you need?
Bloody footsteps
leading up to the door?
문에서 나온 피 묻은 발자국?
One thing I don't need is heckling.
전화할 땐 부탁조더니
You called me and asked for help.
Now you're behaving like a taxpayer.
이젠 아주 뻔뻔하게 나오시는데!
How did we ever
stand each other in that plane
전쟁 3년 간 어떻게
한 비행기에서 지냈는지 몰라
For three years during the war?
I guess I'll go over
to the railroad station
기차역에 가서
쏜월드의 주장을 확인해 볼께
And check on Thorwald's story.
Oh, forget about the story.
그걸 깜빡했군
시체가 들어있는 가방을 찾아봐
Find the trunk. Mrs Thorwald's in it.
Oh, I almost forgot.
쏜월드에게 엽서가 한 장 와 있더군
There was a postcard
in Thorwald's mailbox. It was...
Mailed 3:30 yesterday
afternoon from Merritsville.
어제 오후 3시 30분에
80마일 떨어진 곳에서 온 거야
That's 80 miles north of here.
Message went: "Arrived OK.
내용은 무사히 도착
Already feeling better. Love, Anna. '
벌써 나은 것 같아요, 안나가
Uh...
Is that, um...
안나가 내가 생각하는 그 부인?
Anna...
Is that who I think it is?
쏜월드 부인이야
- Mrs Thorwald.
- Uh-huh.
더 필요한 게 있나?
Oh, so anything you need, Jeff?
You might send me a good detective.
훌륭한 형사 하나 보내주게
- 진은 없어?
- 가져올께요
너무 빨라, 왼쪽 팔을 들구
- "Hello? Yes?"
- Hello, Miss Doyle?
- 여보세요?
- 도일 부인?
톰은 아직 안 들어왔나요?
This is Jeff again.
Has Tom come in yet?
"Not yet, Jeff. "
그런데요
You mean you haven't
even heard from him?
아직 연락조차 없었단 말인가요?
"Not a word.
Is it something really important, Jeff?"
없었어요
중요한 일인가요?
Yeach, I'm afraid it is.
그래요
"I'll have him call the moment
I hear from him. "
들어오면 즉시 연락 드리라고 할께요
No, no, don't bother to do that.
그럴 필요 없구요
Just have him get over here
as soon as he can.
될 수 있는 한
빨리 오라고 하세요
Looks like Thorwald's
pulling out tonight.
쏜월드가 오늘 밤
도망칠 것 같다고요
- " Who's Thorwald?"
- He'll know, he'll know.
- 쏜월드가 누구죠?
- 그렇게 말하면 알 겁니다
And Thorwald's a man, don't worry.
남자니까 걱정은 마시구요
- "Good night, you idiot. "
- Good night.
- 알았어요
- 안녕히 계세요
또 장거리 전화야
Long distance again.
There's somebody at the door.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hello.
안녕
머리를 어떻게 한 거야?
- What'd you do to your hair?
- Oh, I just -
Take a look at Thorwald.
He's getting ready to pull out.
쏜월드를 좀 봐
아주 떠나려나봐
He doesn't seem to be in any hurry.
서두르는 기색은 없는데요
물건을 전부 꺼내놓고 있어
He's been laying out all
his things on one of the beds:
Shirts, suits, coats, socks.
셔츠, 양복, 코트, 양말
- 부인 악어 핸드백까지 말야
- 그래요?
Even that alligator handbag
his wife left on the bedpost.
장롱 안에 숨겨 뒀더라구
최소한 거기 있었어
He had it hidden in the dresser.
At least, it was there.
그걸 꺼내더니
장거리 전화를 걸었어
He took it out, went to the telephone
and made a long distance call.
핸드백 안에
부인 보석이 들어 있었어
He had his wife's jewellery
in the handbag.
Seemed worried about it.
Asked someone's advice over the phone.
그게 걱정 돼서 누군가에게
자문을 구하는 눈치였어
Someone not his wife.
부인이 아니고요?
Well, I never saw him
ask her for advice.
부인에게 뭘 묻는 건
한번도 본 적이 없어
She volunteered plenty,
but I never saw him ask her for any.
- I wonder where he's going.
- I don't know.
- 어딜 가는 걸까요?
- 모르겠어
- Suppose he doesn't come back?
- He'll be back. His things are there.
- 다시 오지 않는 게 아닐까요?
- 돌아올 거야, 짐이 아직 있는 걸
- I guess it's safe to put on lights.
- No, not yet!
- 불을 켜는 게 좋겠어요
- 그냥 있어봐!
OK, you can turn it on now. He must
have gone someplace to the right.
이제 켜도 돼
오른쪽으로 갔어
하루종일 일에
전념하려고 노력했어요
All day long, I've been trying
to keep my mind on my work.
- Thinking about Thorwald?
- And you, and your friend, Doyle.
- 쏜월드 생각 때문에?
- 당신과 도일 생각도요
- Did you hear from him since he left?
- Not a word.
- 그 후 다시 연락 있었어요?
- 없었어
He said he was gonna check
the railroad station and the trunk.
기차역에 가서
가방을 조사한다고 했는데
거기 있을 거야
He must be still at it.
Something on your mind?
생각이 떠올랐어?
- 이해가 안 돼요
- 뭐가?
- It doesn't make sense to me.
- What doesn't?
여자는 그렇게 부주의하지 않아요
Women aren't that unpredictable.
Hmm. Well, I can't guess
what you're thinking.
무슨 소린지 모르겠는데
A woman has a favourite handbag,
여자는 아끼는 핸드백은
침대 머리맡에 놓는 법이에요
And it always hangs on her bedpost
where she can get at it easily.
그런데 갑자기 여행을 떠나면서
그걸 두고 가다니요
Then, all of a sudden, she goes away
on a trip and leaves it behind. Why?
Because she didn't know
she was going on a trip,
여행가는 줄 몰랐거나
가방이 필요 없는 곳이었거나
And where she's going,
she wouldn't need the handbag.
Yes, but only her husband
would know that.
그야 남편만이 알겠죠
여자는 보석을 가방에 넣지 않아요
And that jewellery - Women don't
keep their jewellery in a purse
Getting all twisted
and scratched and tangled up.
흠집이 나거든요
그럼 남편 옷 사이에 숨겨두나?
Well, do they hide it
in their husband's clothes?
아뇨, 그리고 떠날 때
두고 가지도 않아요
They do not.
And they don't leave it behind either.
Why, a woman going anywhere
but the hospital
병원에 가는 게 아니라면
어딜 가든 치장을 하니까요
Would always take make-up,
perfume and jewellery.
Put that over there.
That's inside stuff, huh?
그런 걸 두고 갈 리 없단 말이지?
It's basic equipment.
그건 기본이에요
And you don't leave it behind in
your husband's drawer
절대 남편 서랍에
가방 채 두고 가진 않죠
In your favourite handbag.
Well, I'm with you, sweetie.
I'm with you.
동감이야
Tom Doyle has a pat answer
for that though.
도일이 무슨 대답을
할 지 궁금하군
That Mrs Thorwald left at 6:00am
yesterday with her husband?
쏜월드 부인이
아침 6시에 떠났다고요?
증인에 의하면
According to those witnesses.
Well, I have a pat rebuttal
for Mr Doyle.
그건 쏜월드 부인이
아니었을 거예요
Couldn't have been Mrs Thorwald,
or I don't know women.
아님 내가 여자를 모르는 거죠
- 목격자는 어떡하고?
- 여자를 보긴 봤겠죠
- What about the witnesses?
- We'll agree they saw a woman,
다만 쏜월드 부인이 아닌 거죠
But she was not Mrs Thorwald.
- That is, not yet.
- Is that so?
그럴까?
이리 와봐
Come here.
I'd like to see your friend's face
when we tell him.
이 얘기를 듣는 당신 친구의
얼굴이 보고 싶군요
He doesn't sound
like much of a detective.
별로 형사답지 못한
사람 같았어요
그건 너무 심한 평가군
열심히 노력하는 사람이야
Oh, don't be too hard on him.
He's a steady worker.
I sure wish he'd show up.
어서 왔으면 좋겠는데
Don't rush him. We have all night.
서두르지 말아요
밤새 있을 거니까
뭐라고?
- We have all what?
- Night.
당신과 함께 밤새 있을 거예요
I'm going to stay with you.
집주인에게 허락을 받아야 할 걸
Well, you'll have to clear that
with my landlord.
주말을 전부 휴가 냈어요
I have the whole weekend off.
좋은 생각이지만
침대는 하나 뿐이야
That's very nice,
but I just have one bed.
If you say anything else, I'll...
Stay tomorrow night too.
더 얘기하면
내일 밤도 있을 거예요
빌려 줄 잠옷도 없는 걸
I won't be able to
give you any... Pyjamas.
가방 하나만 들고
다녀야 한다고 했죠?
You said I'll have
to live out of one suitcase.
- I'll bet yours isn't this small.
- This is a suitcase?
당신 건 이렇게 작진 않을 걸요
이게 가방이야?
마크 크로스 가방이에요
Well, a Mark Cross overnight case.
작지만 속은 넓어요
- Ooh.
- Compact, but, uh... Ample enough.
Looks like you packed in a hurry.
짐을 서둘러 싼 것 같군
Look at this. Isn't that amazing?
정말 놀라운데
침대를 하룻밤 빌리고
제 직감을 빌려드리죠
I'll trade you... My feminine
intuition for a bed for the night.
I'll go along with that.
당신 말에 따르지
또 그 노래에요
There's that song again.
저런 노래를 만드는 영감은
어디서 나오는 걸까요?
Where does a man get inspiration
to write a song like that?
한 달에 한번
여주인을 만나면 생길 걸
Well, he gets it from
the landlady once a month.
It's utterly beautiful.
정말 아름다워요
- I wish I could be creative.
- Oh, sweetie, you are.
나도 저런 재능이
있으면 좋겠어요
당신도 있어, 어려운 상황을
만드는 데는 천재잖아
Y- Y-You have a great talent for
creating difficult situations.
- 제가요?
- 그럼
- I do?
- Sure.
Like staying here all night uninvited.
여기서 밤을 새겠다는 것도 그렇고
Well, surprise is the most
important element of attack.
최선의 공격은 기습이에요
엿보다 들키면 어떡할 거예요?
Besides, you're not up on
your private eye literature.
그럴 땐 여자가 있어야
빠져 나올 수 있다구요
When they're in trouble,
it's always their Girl Friday
That gets them out of it.
Is she the girl that
saves them from the clutches
부잣집 딸의 열정을
빠져 나올 땐 어떻게 하지?
Of the over-passionate
daughters of the rich?
- The same.
- That's the one, huh?
- 마찬가지죠
- 그렇군
그래도 결국 그녀와는
결혼하지 못 하잖아
It's funny. He never ends
up marrying her, does he?
- That's strange.
- Weird.
- 정말 이상해
- 괴상하죠
Why don't I slip into something
more comfortable?
편한 옷으로 갈아입을께요
By all means.
얼마든지
I mean, like the kitchen
and make us some coffee.
커피 한 잔 만들어 올까요?
Oh, and some brandy too, huh?
브랜디도 넣어서
해리!
Harry.
- 제프
- 어서 오게
- Jeff.
- Hi.
What else have you got
on this man Thorwald?
쏜월드에 대해 또 뭘 알아냈나?
Enough to scare me you wouldn't
show up in time and we'd lose him.
자네가 일찍 나타나지 않았으면
그 놈을 놓쳤을 거야
- 여길 떠날 것 같아?
- 마치 짐을 꾸릴 사람처럼
- Think he's getting out of here?
- He's got everything he owns
Laid out over there in the bedroom,
waiting to be packed.
있는 물건을 전부 꺼내 놨어
I'm just warming some brandy.
Mr Doyle, I presume?
브랜디를 데우고 있어요
도일 씨 맞죠?
Tom, this is Miss Lisa Fremont.
- 톰, 여긴 리사 프리몬트 양이야
- 안녕하십니까?
- How do you do?
- We think Thorwald's guilty.
쏜월드는 살인자에요
조심하게, 톰
Careful, Tom.
- 여보세요
- 도일 경사님요
- Hello.
- Lieutenant Doyle.
여기 있습니다
자네 전화야
Yeach, he's right here. For you.
- Hello.
- Lieutenant Doyle, sir?
- 여보세요?
- 도일 경사님이십니까?
Speaking. Yeach.
그래, 나야
Alright.
I see. Thank you...
Goodbye.
그래 수고했네
커피는 금방 될 거예요
Coffee will be ready soon.
보석에 대해 얘기 안 해요?
Jeff, aren't you going to tell him
about the jewellery?
Jewellery?
보석?
부인 보석을 자신의 옷 속에
숨겨 놓았어
He's got his wife's jewellery hidden
in his clothes in the bedroom there.
- You sure it belonged to his wife?
- It was in her favourite handbag.
- 부인 보석인 게 확실해?
- 부인 핸드백에 들어있었어요
Mr Doyle, that can only lead
to one conclusion.
도일 씨, 결론은 하나 뿐이에요
뭐죠?
Namely?
That it was not Mrs Thorwald that
left with him yesterday morning.
어제 아침에 나간 여자는
쏜월드 부인이 아니었어
그걸 밝혀냈군?
You figured that out, eh?
It's simply that women
don't leave their jewellery behind
그래, 여자는 여행을 떠나면서
보석을 두고 가진 않아요
When they go on a trip.
Come on, Tom. You don't really need
any of this information, do you?
이런 정보는 필요 없는 거지, 그렇지?
As a matter of fact, I don't.
사실 필요 없어
라스 쏜월드에게선
전혀 혐의를 찾아볼 수 없어
Lars Thorwald is no more
a murderer than I am.
그의 행동을 전부
설명할 수 있단 말인가?
You can explain everything
that's going on over there?
아니
No, and neither can you.
사생활이란 그런 거야
That's a secret, private world
you're looking into out there.
사적 공간에선 전혀
이해할 수 없는 행동들을 하지
People do a lot of things in private
they couldn't do in public.
Like disposing of their wives?
아내를 살인하는 거요?
Get that idea out of your mind.
It'll only lead in the wrong direction.
그 생각은 접어 두세요
오해만 생기니까요
What about the knife and the saw?
식칼과 톱은?
- 자넨 톱을 가져 본 적이 없나?
- 우리 집 차고에...
- Did you ever own a saw?
- Well, at home in the garage I had -
그걸로 몇 명이나 죽였지?
How many people
did you cut up with it?
Or with the couple hundred knives
you've owned in your lifetime?
자네도 식칼은 수없이 가져봤지?
논리에 맞지를 않아
Your logic is backward.
부인의 실종과 트렁크
보석에 대해선 어떻죠?
You can't ignore the disappearance
and the trunk and the jewellery.
I checked the railroad station.
He bought a ticket.
역에 조회해 봤더니
표를 끊어서
Ten minutes later,
he put his wife on the train.
부인을 태워 보냈다는군요
Destination: Merritsville.
The witnesses are that deep.
목적지는 매리츠빌
증거가 이만큼 탄탄해
That might have been a woman, but
it couldn't have been Mrs Thorwald.
여자는 있었지만
쏜월드 부인은 아니었고...
- That jewellery
- Look, Miss Fremont.
프리몬트 양, 여자의 직감으로
잡지는 팔리겠지만
That feminine intuition stuff
sells magazines
실생활에선 도움이 안 됩니다
But in real life, it's still a fairy tale.
여자의 직감을 따랐다가
허탕친 게 몇 번인지 아십니까?
I don't know how many
wasted years I've spent,
Tracking down leads
based on female intuition.
알았네
자넨 트렁크를 못 찾고
Alright!
I take it you didn't find the trunk.
All this is from an old speech
you made at the policemen's ball.
빈 소리만 하고 있는 거야
여길 떠난 지 30분만에
트렁크를 찾았네
I found the trunk
a half-hour after I left here.
I suppose it's normal for a man
to tie up a trunk with heavy rope?
굵은 로프로
트렁크를 묶는 게 정상인가요?
If the lock is broken, yes.
자물쇠가 고장나면 그렇죠
트렁크 안에 뭐가 있던가?
What did you find inside the trunk,
a surly note to me?
Mrs Thorwald's clothes;
쏜월드 부인의 옷가지였네
Clean, well-packed,
not stylish, but presentable.
새 건 아니지만 깨끗하더군
Didn't you take them off
to the crime lab?
범죄 실험실에 가져가 봤나요?
I sent them on their merry
and legal way.
원래 목적지로 보냈습니다
Why, when a woman is taking
a simple, short trip,
간단한 여행길에
왜 옷을 전부 보내는 거지?
Does she take everything she owns?
여자의 심리로 해석할 수
있지 않을까?
Let's let the female psychology
department handle that one.
I would say it looked as if
she wasn't coming back.
돌아오지 않을 것처럼 보이는 군요
그야 가정 문제죠
That's what's
known as a family problem.
돌아오지 않는다면
왜 주인에게 말하지 않은 거지?
If she wasn't coming back,
why didn't he tell his landlord?
I'll tell you why
he didn't tell his landlord,
그 이유는 한가지
숨기는 게 있기 때문이야
Because he was hiding something.
자넨 주인에게 모든 걸 말하나?
Do you tell your landlord everything?
조심하라고 했지
Ah, I told you to be careful, Tom.
내가 조심해서
비행기를 몰지 않았다면
If I'd have been careful
piloting that reconnaissance plane
자넨 지금 사진 기자로
명성을 떨치고 있지 못 할 거야
You wouldn't have had the chance
to take the pictures
That won you a medal,
and a good job, and fame, and money.
What do you say, we all sit
down and have a nice friendly drink.
우리 즐겁게 술이나 마시는 게 어때?
Forget all about this.
전부 잊어버리고 말이야
We can tell lies about
the good old days during the war.
전쟁 땐 거짓말은
금방 들통이 나곤 했는데 말이야
You mean
you're through with the case?
이 사건은 끝이란 말인가요?
There is no case
to be through with, Miss Fremont.
끝내고 말고 할 것도 없어요
How about that drink?
술 한잔 하실까요?
Yeach, I guess you're right.
자네가 옳아
Well, I think I better get home
and get some sleep.
집에 가서 잠이나 자는 게 좋겠어
Cheers.
I, uh...
I'm not much of a snifter.
제가 칠칠치 못해서 말이죠
Oh, Jeff, if you need any more help...
도움이 필요하면
Consult the Yellow Pages
in your telephone directory.
전화번호부를 뒤져보게나
퇴장 대사가 멋지군요
Oh, I love funny exiting lines.
- Who was that trunk addressed to?
- Mrs Anna Thorwald.
- 트렁크의 수취인이 누구야?
- 안나 쏜월드 부인
Then let's wait and find out
who picks it up.
그럼 누가 와서
가져가나 보면 되겠군
Oh, that phone call,
I gave them your number.
내가 자네 번호를 일러놨는데
- I hope you don't mind.
- Depends on who they were.
- 괜찮겠나?
- 누구냐에 따라 다르지
The police at Merritsville.
매리츠빌 경찰이야
They reported
the trunk was just picked up...
가방은 안나 쏜월드가 받아갔대
By Mrs Anna Thorwald.
Don't stay up too late.
너무 늦게 자지 말게
- Look.
- What?
- 봐요!
- 뭘?
Yeach, he's kind of young, isn't he?
너무 젊군
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거예요?
You know, much as I hate to give
Thomas J Doyle too much credit,
도일 말을 인정하긴 정말 싫지만
He might have gotten ahold
of something when he said
사생활 침해라는 것
하나는 맞는 것 같아
That was pretty private
stuff going on out there.
I wonder if it's ethical to watch a man
망원경으로 이웃을 엿보는 게
윤리적으로 괜찮은 걸까?
With binoculars and a long-focus lens.
Do you...
범죄가 아니라고 해도
윤리적으로 문제가 없는 걸까?
Do you suppose it's ethical, even if you
prove that he didn't commit a crime?
엿보는 취미 같은 것엔
관심 없어요
I'm not much on rear window ethics.
Of course,
they can do the same thing to me,
나도 똑같이 당할 수 있겠지
관찰을 당하듯이 말이야
Watch me like a bug under a glass,
if they want to.
Jeff, if someone came in here,
they wouldn't believe what they'd see.
우리가 이러는 걸
다른 사람이 보면 이상하겠죠?
- What?
- You and me with long faces,
- 뭐가?
- 살인이 일어나지 않았다고
Plunged into despair because
we find out a man didn't kill his wife.
낙담하고 있는 우리 말이에요
We're two of the most
frightening ghouls I've ever known.
우리같이 이상한 성격을
가진 사람도 없을 거예요
You'd think we could be a bit happy
that the poor woman is alive and well.
그 부인이 살아있다는 걸
기뻐해야 하는 거 아닐까요?
Whatever happened to that old
saying, "Love thy neighbour'?
네 이웃을 사랑하라
하지 않았던가요
You know, I think I'll start
reviving that tomorrow.
그건 내일부터 생각하려고 했는데
좋아, 그럼 미스 육체파부터
시작해 볼까?
Yeach, I'll begin with Miss Torso.
Not if I have to move into
an apartment across the way...
그럼 내가 반대편 아파트로
이사하는 수가 있어요
배일 춤을 매 시간 출 수도 있다구요
And do the "Dance of the Seven Veils'
every hour.
Show's over for tonight.
오늘 밤 공연은 끝났어요
Preview of coming attractions.
또 다른 즐거움을 기대하세요
Did Mr Doyle think I stole this case?
도일 씨가 이걸
사건이라고 생각할까요?
No, Lisa, I don't think he did.
아니, 그렇게 생각하진 않을 걸
- What do you think?
- Well, uh...
- 무슨 생각해요?
- 그냥...
- I will rephrase the question.
- Thank you.
- 질문을 바꿔보죠
- 고마워
Do you like it?
맘에 들어요?
- Yes, I like it.
- Well -
그래, 맘에 들어
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
- Somebody's hurt?
- It's the dog.
누가 다쳤어?
개가 다쳤어
어떻게 된 거야?
Something's happened to the dog.
Somebody fall out a window?
누가 창문에서 떨어뜨렸나?
I think it's a dog.
개가 죽었어!
It's dead. It's been strangled.
Its neck is broken.
목이 부러져서 죽었어!
Which one of you did it?
누가 그랬어?
Which one of you killed my dog?
누가 내 개를 죽인 거야?
You don't know the meaning
of the word "neighbours'.
너희는 이웃이란 말의 뜻도 몰라?
Neighbours like each other,
서로 돕고 사랑하고
Speak to each other,
care if anybody lives or dies!
생사에 관심을 가져주고!
But none of you do!
너희는 하나도 그렇지 않아!
착한 개를 죽일 정도로
못됐을 줄이야!
But I couldn't imagine
any of you being so low
That you'd kill a helpless, friendly dog.
The only thing in this whole
neighbourhood who liked anybody!
모든 사람을 좋아하고 따랐는데!
너무 따르는 게 귀찮아서
죽인 거야? 따르는 게 싫었어?
Did you kill him because he liked you?
Just because he liked you?
안으로 들어가요
Let's go inside.
안으로 다시 들어가지
- Come on. Let's go back in.
- It's only a dog.
You know, for a minute,
that Tom Doyle almost had me
하마터면 내가 잘못
생각했는 줄 알 뻔했어
Convinced I was wrong.
- But you're not?
- Look.
- 아닌가요?
- 봐...
In the courtyard, only one person
didn't come to the window. Look.
여기서 내다보지 않은 집은
딱 한군데 뿐이야
Why would Thorwald
want to kill a little dog?
개를 왜 죽였을까요?
아는 게 너무 많아서?
Because it knew too much?
하루종일 지켜볼 가치가 있는 걸까?
You think this is worth
waiting all day to see?
청소를 하는 건가요?
Is he cleaning house?
He's washing down the bathroom walls.
목욕탕 벽을 씻어 내리고 있어
Hm, must have splattered a lot.
많이 튀었을 테니까요
다들 그 생각을 하고 있잖아요?
Well, why not?
That's what we're all thinking.
He killed her in there,
he has to clean up those stains.
저기서 죽였으니까 떠나기 전에
흔적을 없애는 거겠죠
Oh, Stella, your choice of words.
아무리 그래도 말이 좀...
살인을 우아하게 말하는 방법을
전 모르겠네요
Nobody ever invented
a polite word for a killing yet.
Lisa, back there on that shelf,
there's a little yellow box, you see it?
리사, 뒤 선반에 가면
노란 상자가 있을 거야
- 위에 있는 거요?
- 그래
- Top one?
- Right on top, yeach.
And bring me the viewer there.
이리로 가져와 봐
I just got a...
These are about two weeks old.
2주 전에 찍은 게 있어
I hope I took something else
besides leg art. Now which one...
어느 거지...
What are you looking for?
뭘 찾는 거예요?
There's something, and if I'm right,
I think I've solved a murder.
찾고 있는 게 있는데 내 생각이
맞다면 사건을 푼 거야
- Mrs Thorwald?
- No.
- 쏜월드 부인 사건을요?
- 아니
No, the dog.
개 말이에요
Uh-huh. I think I know
why Thorwald killed that dog.
쏜월드가 왜 개를 죽였는지 알겠어
이걸 보고 뭐가 다른 지 말해봐
Here, now you take a look.
Tell me what you see.
Now take it down.
내려 봐
Now look again.
다시 보고
Now take it down. You see?
내리고... 보여?
It's just a picture of the backyard -
그저 뒤 뜰 풍경인데요
But with one important change.
One important change.
달라진 게 있어
Those flowers
in Thorwald's pet flower bed.
쏜월드 정원의 꽃을 봐
You mean where the dog
was sniffing around?
개가 킁킁대며 다닌 곳 말인가요?
Where the dog was digging.
Now look at those flowers.
땅을 파던 곳 말이야
그 꽃들을 봐요
Look, those two yellow zinnias
on this end
끝에 있는 노란색 꽃을 봐요
Aren't as tall as they were.
2주일 사이에
키가 작아지는 꽃도 있나?
Since when do flowers
grow shorter in two weeks?
- There's something buried there.
- Mrs Thorwald.
- 뭔가를 묻었군요
- 쏜월드 부인!
You haven't spent much time
around cemeteries, have you?
묘지에 가 보신 적이
별로 없으시군요?
Mr Thorwald could scarcely
put his wife's body
저렇게 작은 곳에
시체를 묻을 순 없어요
In a plot of ground
about one foot square.
Unless, of course,
he put her in standing on end,
세워서 묻었다면 모르지만
And then he wouldn't need
a knife and saw.
그럼 톱과 칼은 필요 없죠
No, my idea is she's
scattered all over town.
시체를 토막내서
여기 저기 뿌린 거예요
- Leg in the East River
- Oh, Stella, please!
- 다리는 강에...
- 스텔라, 그만해요!
그래도 뭔가 있어
저 꽃은 다시 심어진 거야
No, no, no. There's something in there.
Those flowers have been
taken out and put back in.
어쩌면 칼과 톱인지도 몰라요
- Maybe it's the knife and saw.
- Yeach -
- 도일 경사를 불러요
- 아뇨
- Call Lieutenant Doyle.
- No, let's wait.
Let's wait till it gets a little darker,
and I'll go over there and dig them up.
어두워질 때까지 기다렸다가
가서 파봐요
You'll go? You won't dig anything up
and get your neck broken.
당신이? 그러다 목이
부러지면 어쩌려고?
No, no, we've...
안돼...
We're not gonna call Doyle until
I can produce Mrs Thorwald's body.
부인의 시체를 찾기 전엔
도일을 부를 수 없어
What we've got to do is find a way
to get into that apartment.
문제는 저 아파트에
들어갈 방법을 찾는 거야
짐을 싸고 있어요
He's packing.
Uh-oh.
연필을 줘봐
Here, get me a pencil.
종이를 가져와요
저기 어디 있을 거예요
Stella, get me some note paper.
It's up here someplace.
There it is.
'부인을 어떻게 했나?'
You did it, Thorwald. You did it.
네 놈 짓이지
쏜월드, 네가 한 짓이야
- Look out, Lisa. He's coming.
- You never should have let her do it.
- 조심해, 리사! 그가 오고 있어!
- 하게 두는 게 아니었어요!
- If he ever
- Look. Look. Look.
잡히기라도 하는 날엔...
Thank heaven that's over.
하느님, 감사합니다
이제 됐군요
- Alright if I have a drink?
- Sure, go ahead.
- 술 한잔해도 될까요?
- 물론이죠
There's no doubt about it. He's leaving.
It's just a question of when.
이젠 의심의 여지가 없어
문제는 언제 떠나느냐야
Mind if I use that portable keyhole?
그 포터볼 열쇠구멍 좀 빌릴까요?
Go ahead, just as long as you tell me
what you're looking at.
뭘 찾는 지만 말한다면요
- I wonder...
- Wonder what?
- 이상하네요
- 뭐가요?
미스 고독이
수면제 같은 약을 꺼냈어요
Miss Lonelyhearts just laid out
something that looks like
Rhodium tri-eckonal capsules.
- You can tell from here?
- I've handled enough of those
- 여기서 보고도 알 수 있나요?
- 수면제라면...
To put everybody in Hackensack
to sleep for the winter.
마을 사람 전부를
재울만한 분량을 다뤘어요
- 그럼 저만큼 먹으면?
- 아뇨, 저 정도면 편히 잠들죠
- Does she have enough of them to
- To make her rest easier -
Wasn't that close?
아슬아슬 했죠?
What was his reaction
when he looked at the note?
그 편지를 보고
반응이 어땠어요?
그런 표정으로 은행돈은
절대 빌릴 수 없겠던데요
It wasn't the kind
of expression that would get him
A quick loan at the bank.
Jeff, the handbag!
제프, 핸드백이에요!
Suppose Mrs Thorwald's wedding ring
쏜월드 부인의 결혼 반지가
저 보석 속에 있다면?
Is among the jewellery
he has in that handbag?
Now, during the phone conversation
he held up three rings:
반지가 세 개 있었어
One with a diamond,
one with a big stone of some sort,
다이아 반지 하나
보석 반지 하나
And then just a plain gold band.
그냥 금반지 하나
The last thing she would leave behind
would be her wedding ring.
결혼 반지를 빼놓고
가는 여자는 없죠
Stella,
do you ever leave yours at home?
스텔라, 결혼 반지를
빼놓고 온 적 있나요?
The only way anybody could get that
ring would be to chop off my finger.
손가락을 자르기 전엔
어림없는 일이죠
Let's go down and find out
what's buried in the garden.
내려가서 뭐가 묻혀 있는 지
파보기로 해요
찬성이에요, 쏜월드 부인
늘 한번 꼭 만나보고 싶었어요
Why not? I've always wanted
to meet Mrs Thorwald.
- 둘이 무슨 얘길 하는 거예요?
- 삽이 있나요?
- What are you two talking about
- You got a shovel?
삽? 물론 없죠
Of course I don't have a shovel.
- There's probably one in the basement.
- If you're squeamish, just don't look.
- 지하에 가면 있을 거예요
- 떨리면 보지 말아요
떨리다니, 난 떨리지 않아!
위험할까봐 그러는 거야!
Squeamish? I'm not squeamish.
I just don't want you two
to end up like that dog.
Oh, you know, Miss Fremont,
he might just have something there.
프리몬트 양
거기 뭐가 있을까요?
Just hold on. Here, take this.
이걸 들고 있어
No sense taking any chances
in this thing.
괜히 위험을 무릅쓸 필요 없어
Here, give me the phone book.
전화번호부 줘봐
왜요?
What for?
Maybe I can
get him out of that apartment.
저 작자를 불러낼 수 있을 거야
We only need a few minutes.
몇 분만 있으면 돼요
I'll see if I can get about 15 minutes.
- 15분 가량 붙들어 볼께요
- 어떻게요?
- How?
- Thorwald.
쏜월드...
Thorwald...
Thorwald.
쏜월드...
Chelsea 2-7099.
첼시아 2-7099
2-7099.
우리가 다시 한번 겁을 주는 거야
We scared him once,
maybe we can scare him again.
I guess I'm using that word
'we" a little freely.
우리라는 말을
써도 되나 모르겠네
You're taking all the chances.
위험한 건 두 사람인데
- 이 사람도 끼워 줄까요, 스텔라?
- 이의 없어요
- Shall we vote him in, Stella?
- Unanimously.
2-7099. Look out.
2-7099...
첼시아...
Chelsea.
어서 받아라, 쏜월드
Go on, pick it up, Thorwald.
네 애인이 건
전화일 수도 있잖아
Go on, you're curious.
You wonder if it's your girlfriend
calling, the one you killed for.
Go on, pick it up.
어서 받아!
- "Hello?"
- Did you get my note?
- 여보세요
- 내 쪽지를 받았소?
Well, did you get it, Thorwald?
받았나요, 쏜월드?
"Who are you?"
- 당신 누구요?
- 알 수 있는 기회를 주지
I'll give you a chance to find out.
Meet me
in the bar at the Albert Hotel.
알버트 호텔 술집에서 만납시다
Do it right away.
당장 나오시오
- "Why should I?"
- A little business meeting...
- 내가 왜?
- 비즈니즈 차...
To settle the estate of your late wife.
부인 재산을 정리하려면
의논을 해야잖소
"I...
Don't know what you mean. "
무슨 뜻인지 모르겠소
Come on. Quit stalling, Thorwald,
시치미 떼지 말아, 쏜월드
Or I'll hang up and call the police.
안 나오면 경찰에 신고할 거야
- "I only have $100."
- That's a start.
- 난 백 달러 밖에 없소
- 선수금으로 받아두지
난 지금 알버트 호텔에 있소
기다리고 있겠소
I'm at the Albert now.
I'll be looking for you.
어서요, 스텔라!
Come on, Stella, let's go.
One of you
keep an eye on this window.
이 쪽 유리창을 보고 있어
If I see him coming back,
I'll signal with a flashbulb.
그가 오면 신호를 할께
도일 씨 댁입니다
"This is the Doyle residence. "
Hello, this is L B Jefferies.
I'm a friend of Mr Doyle.
전 도일의 친구인
제프리라고 합니다
- 누구시죠?
- 애기 보는 사람이에요
- Who's this?
- "This is a baby-sitter. "
Oh, uh...
When do you expect them in?
언제 들어오실 지 아십니까?
"They went to dinner and
maybe a nightclub. "
저녁 먹고
아마 클럽에도 갈 거예요
그렇군요
I see, hm.
If he calls in, have him get
in touch with L B Jefferies?
전화가 오면 제프리에게
전화하라고 전해 주십시오
놀랄 일이 있다구요
I might have quite a surprise for him.
"Well, do we have
your number, Mr Jefferies?"
전화번호는 아시나요?
- He has it. Good night.
- "Good night. "
- 네, 압니다, 수고하세요
- 안녕히 계세요
Ah, Stella was wrong
about Miss Lonelyhearts.
미스 고독에 대해선
스텔라가 오해했군
리사, 뭐 하는 거야?
Lisa, what are you...
Don't...
안돼...
Lisa, what are you doing? Don't go...
뭐 하는 거야
들어가면 안돼!
Li...
Come on, come on!
Get out of there!
어서 나와!
쏜월드가 돌아오면
그 집으로 전화하래요
She said ring Thorwald's phone
the second you see him come back.
- We'll ring right now!
- Give her another minute.
- 지금 전화하겠어
- 아뇨, 잠깐만 기다려봐요
Alright, fellows,
let's try it once from the beginning.
Miss Lonelyhearts.
미스 고독이...
Oh, call the police!
경찰을 불러요!
- "Operator. "
- Get me the police, sixth precinct.
경찰을 대 주세요!
6구역이요
알겠습니다
"Yes, sir. "
Mr Jefferies, the music stopped her.
제프리 씨... 음악을 듣고
포기했어요
What...
Lisa!
리사!
"Precinct Six, Sergeant Allgood. "
6구역 올 굿 형사입니다
Hello. Look, a man is assaulting
a woman at 125 West Ninth Street,
125번 가 서쪽 도로에서
여자가 폭행 당하고 있어요
Second floor, at the rear.
빨리 오세요!
Make it fast!
- "Your name?"
- L B Jefferies.
- 이름은요?
- 제프리요
- "Phone number?"
- Chelsea 2-5598
- 전화번호는?
- 첼시 2-5598
"Two minutes. "
The door was open.
문이 열려 있었어요
Oh...
- I told you...
- Oh, no!
맙소사!
놔 줘요! 제프!
Let go of me! Jeff!
- Oh, no!
- Jeff! Jeff!
- 안돼!
- 제프!
Jeff!
제프!
Lisa!
스텔라, 어떡하면 좋지?
Stella, what do we do?
- 제프, 제프
- 저기 와요
- Jeff! Jeff!
- Here they come.
뭘 하는 거죠?
그냥 넘기지 않고?
What's she trying to do?
Why doesn't she turn him in?
- She's a smart girl.
- "Smart girl?" She'll be arrested.
- 똑똑한 여자야
- 똑똑해요? 체포 됐는데요?
It'll get her out of there, won't it?
그야 꺼내면 되지
Look, the wedding ring!
봐, 결혼 반지야!
Turn off the light! He's seen us!
불을 꺼요, 우릴 봤어요!
How long do you think he'll stay there?
저기 얼마나 있을까?
Unless he's dumber than I think,
he won't wait until his lease is up.
바보가 아니라면 도망치겠죠
Get my billfold out of the drawer
in the table there.
서랍에서 수표책을 꺼내요
- What do you need money for?
- I'm gonna bail Lisa out of jail.
- 돈은 뭐하게요?
- 리사를 보석으로 꺼내야죠
You could leave her there
till next Tuesday.
화요일까지 경찰서에 있으면
Then you could sneak
safely away as planned.
몰래 도망칠 수도 있을 텐데요
- Yeach, let's see, $127.
- How much do you need?
- 어디... 127달러로군
- 얼마나 필요하죠?
Well, this is first offence burglary,
that's about $250.
적어도 250은 있어야 할 거예요
- Lisa's handbag.
- Yeach.
리사의 가방...
- How much does she have?
- Fifty cents.
- 얼마나 들었죠?
- 50센트요
- Here, take this.
- I got $20 or so in my purse.
- 이걸 가져가요
- 나한테도 20달러 가량 있어요
나머진 어떡하구요?
What about the rest?
When those cops see Lisa,
they'll even contribute.
리사를 보면
경찰들도 기부를 할 걸요
서둘러요!
Just a minute. Hurry up!
잠깐만요, 서둘러요!
- 제프입니다
- 이번엔 무슨 일인가?
- Jefferies.
- "What is it now?"
도일, 큰 건수를 잡았어
Doyle, I've got something
really big for you.
전화를 하는 게 아닌데
"Why did I have to return your call?"
또 살인이니 어쩌니 한다면...
"Look! Don't louse up my night
with another mad killer -"
내 말 들어
리사가 잡혀갔어!
Listen to me! Listen to me!
Lisa's in jail. She got arrested.
- "Your Lisa?"
- My Lisa.
- 자네 리사가?
- 내 리사!
Boy, you should have seen her.
She got into Thorwald's apartment,
리사가 쏜월드 아파트에
들어간 거야
But then he came back
and the only way I could get her out,
그녀를 구할 방법은
경찰을 부르는 것뿐이었어
Was call the police.
- "I told you -"
- I know you told me.
- 전에 말했잖아...
- 리사가 증거를 갖고 나왔어
She went in to get evidence,
and she came out with evidence.
어떤 증거?
- "Like what?"
- Like Mrs Thorwald's wedding ring.
쏜월드 부인의
결혼 반지라면 어떻겠나?
If that woman was alive,
she'd be wearing that ring, right?
살아 있다면
끼고 있어야 하지 않겠나?
- "Hm. It's a possibility. "
- A "possibility'? It's a fact.
- 가능성은 있지
- 가능성?
He killed a dog last night
정원을 팠던 개를 그가 죽였어
왠지 알아?
Because the dog was scratching around
in the garden. You know why?
Because he had something buried
in that garden that the dog scented.
정원에 묻은 걸
개가 냄새를 맡은 거야
"Like an old ham bone?"
뼈다귀 같은 거 말인가?
I don't know what pet names
Thorwald had for his wife,
부인 이름이 뭔지는 모르겠지만
But I'll tell you this:
All those trips at night
with that metal suitcase,
그 가방을 들고
밤에 들락거린 것은
소지품을 나른 게 아니야
He wasn't taking out his possessions,
Because his possessions
are still up in the apartment.
소지품은 전부 집에 있어
'Do you think perhaps
it was old "ham bone?"'
그럼 뼈다귀란 말인가?
그래, 토막을 내서...
And I'll tell you something else.
그가 건 전화는
전부 장거리 전화였네
All the telephone calls
he made were long distance, alright?
부인에게 한 전화였다면
도착했다는 편지는 왜 했을까?
Now, if he called his wife long
distance on the day she left,
After she arrived in Merritsville,
Why did she write a card to him
saying she arrived in Merritsville?
이미 통화를 했으면서 말야
Why did she do that?
- "Where'd they take Lisa?"
- Precinct six.
- 리사는 어디로 갔나?
- 6구역 경찰서
I sent somebody over
with the bail money.
보석금을 갖고 사람을 보내겠네
"Maybe you won't need it.
I'll run it down, Jeff. "
그럴 필요 없어
내가 내려가 보겠네
Alright. Hurry up, will you?
This fellow knows he's being watched.
좋아, 서둘러 주게
그 놈은 감시 받는 줄 알아
He's not gonna wait around forever.
Hurry up.
꾸물대고 있을 놈이 아니야
"If that ring checks out,
we'll give him an escort. So long, Jeff. "
전화를 조회해 보면
소환할 수 있을 거야
So long.
여보세요?
쏜월드가 떠난 것 같아
Hello, Tom.
I think Thorwald's left. I don't see...
Hello?
여보세요?
What do you want from me?
원하는 게 뭐냐?
Your friend, the girl, could have
turned me in. Why didn't she?
네 여자가 날 넘길 수 있었는데
왜 그러지 않았지?
What is it you want, a lot of money?
I don't have any money.
원하는 게 뭐야, 돈?
난 돈은 없어
뭐라고 말 좀 해!
Say something.
원하는 게 뭐냐니까!
Say something! Tell me what you want!
Can you get me that ring back?
반지를 돌려줄 수 있나?
- No.
- Tell her to bring it back.
- 아니
- 이리로 갖고 오라고 해!
I can't. The police have it by now.
이미 경찰에 넘어 갔어
리사, 도일!
Lisa! Doyle!
What was that?
무슨 일이지?
Look! Look over at that apartment!
They're fighting!
저기요, 저걸 봐요!
싸우고 있어요
Look, he's throwing him
out the window!
사람을 떨어뜨리려고 하고 있어
도일!
Doyle!
Creele, give me your. 38!
38구경 이리 내!
미안하네, 제프!
최대한 빨리 온 거네
I'm sorry, Jeff.
I got here as fast as I could.
아무도 건드리지 말아요
이층에서 구급약 갖다 줘요
Don't let anybody touch him.
Get me a medical bag from upstairs.
리사, 당신이 어떻게 됐었다면...
Lisa, sweetie, if anything
had happened to you -
말하지 말아요
난 괜찮아요
- I'm alright.
- Gee, I'm proud of you.
당신이 자랑스러워
이젠 수색 영장 나올까?
You got enough
for a search warrant now?
- 물론이지
- 도일 경사님!
Oh, yeach, sure.
- Lieutenant Doyle.
- Yeach?
- 괜찮습니까?
- 죽진 않았어
- Is he OK?
- He's alive.
쏜월드가 이스트 강으로
안내하겠답니다
Thorwald's ready to take us
on a tour of the East River.
정원엔 뭘 묻었다던가?
Did he say what was buried
in the flower bed?
Yeach. He said the dog got
too inquisitive, so he dug it up.
개가 하도 귀찮게 해서
다시 파냈답니다
집에 있는 모자 상자에
들었다는데요
It's in a hat box over in his apartment.
- 보시겠습니까?
- 아뇨
- Want to look?
- No, thanks.
보고 싶지 않아요
I don't want any part of her.
히트를 쳤으면 좋겠어요
처음 내 놓는 건데
I hope it's gonna be a hit.
This is the first release.
들어보고 싶어요
I'd love to hear it.
당신 음악이 내게 얼마나
중요한 지 모르실 거예요
I can't tell you what
this music has meant to me.
귀여운 우리 강아지
Oh, sweet little puppy.
다신 뛰어내리지 말아라
Don't jump. Let's try it again, puppy.
Stay still. Stay.
스탠리!
- Stanley!
- Hello, baby.
군대 가더니 더 멋있어졌어
My, look what
the army's done for you!
배가 고픈데
The army's made me hungry.
아이스박스엔 뭐가 들었지?
What have you got
in the icebox to eat?
집에 오니 좋군
Boy, it's good to be home.
실업자인 줄 알았으면
If you had told me you'd quit your job,
결혼하지 않았을 거예요
We wouldn't have gotten married.
왜 그래, 당신...
Oh, honey. Come on.